<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>HydroGadget</title><link href="http://hydrogadget.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://hydrogadget.org/feeds/all-en.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://hydrogadget.org/</id><updated>2012-12-02T00:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>HydroGadget: Leaving Our Mark on The Internet of Things</title><link href="http://hydrogadget.org/2012/12/02/hydrogadget-leaving-our-mark-on-the-internet-of-things/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-02T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Brian Munroe</name></author><id>tag:hydrogadget.org,2012-12-02:2012/12/02/hydrogadget-leaving-our-mark-on-the-internet-of-things/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Do tell, what is a HydroGadget?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A personal commentary by one the HydroGadget team member&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So a while back, I was standing in my garage, middle of the night, trying to figure out how to program
my sprinkler timer to meet the new watering restrictions that the city had inacted
in Las Vegas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to schedule it to water three days a week, twice a day...Ok, that seems
easy enough, right?  Lets see here, what does this dial do...how about this thing
that toggles between program A and B...and then program 1 and 2?...Wait a minute, A and B?
1 and 2?  What on earth does all this mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHO DESIGNED THIS THING?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After about 30 minutes of fumbling through a crazy interface, I think I got the
timer programmed correctly, or so I hoped...guess I'll have to wait until tomorrow to find out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make a long story short, I lucked out that time, but I seriously wanted to do
something about the interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Enter, HydroGadget (and SYN Shop, and Mini-Maker Faire LV, and group of BFFs)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after wandering aimlessly trying to learn microelectronics, I had assembled a
few kits, played with the Arduino -- but I really didn't understand what I was
doing.  I was just following recipes that someone else had designed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the upcoming &lt;a href="http://makerfairevegas.com/" title="Las
Vegas Mini Maker Faire"&gt;Las Vegas Mini Maker Faire&lt;/a&gt;, I really wanted to throw my hat into the ring as a
maker.  I'm currently the president of &lt;a href="https://synshop.org/" title="SYN Shop"&gt;SYN Shop&lt;/a&gt;
and I have nothing to show for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulling in a few friends that I work with (Charles and Mike), we all decided that
we'd head down this road together.  We all have about the same level of experience
with electronics but we all think this project sounds interesting and is going to
be a great way to take our electronics skills to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Hardware Startup"></category></entry></feed>