<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>HydroGadget</title><link href="http://hydrogadget.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://hydrogadget.org/feeds/Design.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://hydrogadget.org/</id><updated>2012-12-03T00:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>Dear Wire Inductance..Go To Hell!</title><link href="http://hydrogadget.org/2012/12/03/dear-wire-inductancego-to-hell/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-03T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Brian Munroe</name></author><id>tag:hydrogadget.org,2012-12-03:2012/12/03/dear-wire-inductancego-to-hell/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We got our first lesson in electical engineering 101 at last night's &lt;a href="https://synshop.org"&gt;SYN
Shop&lt;/a&gt; meetup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the requirements for the device is to use the existing irrigation
controller power supply.  To use this, we needed to convert the power from 24VAC to
5VDC.  Having never done this before and always up for the challenge, I fired up the internet and tried to determine
what components we needed to build our own power supply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ordering about $10 worth of parts (RF choke?  Whatever that is!) I tried my hand
at assembling the circuit following the data sheet from the DC-DC converter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/kbABb.jpg?sss" alt="" title="Hosted by imgur.com" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After wiring it up, I was too tired and scared to plug it in to test it, so I
waited until the SYN Shop meetup to get a second set of eyes on my circuit.  At
the meetup, my good friend Josh looked over the converter datasheet and my wiring
job, gave me the thumbs up and I plugged it in.  Putting the volt meter on the
output leads....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Zero volts &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awe man, now what is wrong?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started picking apart my circuit, looking for mistakes and trying to confirm
that I hadn't blown a part somewhere along the way.  After about 10 minutes of
doing that and finally throwing my hands up in the air, two SYN Shop regulars, Charley and Nathan came over and started looking at what I was doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charley asked a few basic questions and finally said, "This circuit is way too
sensitive to inductance for you to be using that rat's nest of jumpers.  You need
to use perfboard and much shorter wire lengths".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nathan confirmed Charley's assessment and retold a story about how he too had
been bitten by this same exact problem.  However, instead of telling me "good
luck!", Nathan went over to his box of components and pulled out an all in one
DC-DC converter, handed it to me and said "Here, just use this"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now, instead of this wild mess of wires and various components (I did learn
what the RF choke does!  Thanks Charley!), the HydroGadget power circuit looks
like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=http://i.imgur.com/lZaf4.jpg" title="Hosted by imgur.com" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a lot of back and forth, I decided that the even though it feels like
cheating using this &lt;a href="http://www.mouser.com/ProductDetail/Murata-Power-Solutions/OKI-78SR-5-15-W36-C/?qs=sGAEpiMZZMtwaiKVUtQsNemMZL4TplJBqOl7845nWHA%3d"&gt;fancy-pants
converter&lt;/a&gt;,
we will suck it for now...probably :-)&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Hardware Startup"></category><category term="Power Supply"></category><category term="Hurt Feelings"></category></entry><entry><title>Fire up Microsoft Project and find a PMP!</title><link href="http://hydrogadget.org/2012/11/19/fire-up-microsoft-project-and-find-a-pmp/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-11-19T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Brian Munroe</name></author><id>tag:hydrogadget.org,2012-11-19:2012/11/19/fire-up-microsoft-project-and-find-a-pmp/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ok, not really...but Charles, Mike and myself have been meeting on a regular basis for about a month
now and we've come up with a dumptruck load of design requirments.  We've pared
it down to a few that we think we can make for the Feb 2nd LV Mini Maker
Faire deadline:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Phase One Reqirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Must be inexpensive to build.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Must have a sensible and intuitive web / mobile interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Must minimize waste - should act as a drop-in replacement for an existing residential
irrigation timer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;THE BIG ONE:  Must be able to communicate with the water utility to determine
the water restriction schedule.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of these requirements are pretty straightforward, but #4 is the most exciting
to me.  Before starting this project, I googled around and found plenty of DIY
sprinkler controllers, but none of them had the ability to communicate with a
third party.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here in Southern Nevada (namely, Las Vegas), we have mandatory drought restriction
watering schedules.  These change on a quarterly basis and usually
customers are notifed via a postcard to adjust them.  People sometimes ignore the
notices, but most of the time, people just forget to change the schedules, even
with the reminder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the HydroGadget, we want to elimate this by allowing the system to
continually poll the water utility to determine the restriction schedule.  It then
would either adjust things automatically or at least send an email / SMS reminder 
that things need to be changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We think this will be something that the water utility would be really interested
in as well.  Eliminating water waste is easy once it is highly automated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we'd like to use the HydroGadget as a demostration platform for
showing how valuable public data APIs are.  Our phase one plans are to screen
scrape the water utility's website to determine the restriction schedule, but
eventually we'd like to work with them to develop a web API that the HydroGadget
and other devices could leverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Choosing Hardware for the Controller&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as choosing a platform, the HydroGadget team members have been playing around with the &lt;a href="http://www.raspberrypi.org/"&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt; and we all think it will make an excellent controller for our project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We originally started to take some inspiration from &lt;a href="http://mightyohm.com/blog/about/"&gt;Jeff
Keyzer's&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://mightyohm.com/blog/2008/10/building-a-wifi-radio-part-1-introduction/"&gt;WiFi
Radio&lt;/a&gt;
project.  Jeff did a really good job of documenting this fantastic project and we
could easily see how it could be adapted to fit our project.  However we decided that
if we wanted to make a production run of these things then using a Wifi router as
our platform would be too wasteful (we'd have to throw away the case and the
router power supply) and it would also be very time consuming to add the required
serial header to the router mainboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Raspberry Pi is a very inexpensive (~$35US) and low power ARM based computer that runs Linux
and has enough general purpose Input-Output (GPIO) that we can control the
sprinkler valve solenoids without having to add a lot of extra components.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Hardware Startup"></category><category term="Raspberry Pi"></category></entry></feed>